(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
市ノ宮 渋滞 帰りの会で
Ichinomiya, traffic jam, at the end-of-day meeting
面倒くさそう 押しつけられてる
Looking annoyed, having things pushed onto me
なにもからなにもまで
From this to that, everything
死語 相槌 まとめ役なら
Dead words, backchanneling, if I'm the mediator
聞き上手 上手にうなずき合ってる
A good listener, nodding along skillfully
仲良しこよしで
Playing nice and friendly
さあ ダダダ 溜まり 溜まり 貯めよ
Now, da-da-da, let it pile up, pile up, save it up
言えないね そんな 強い言葉は
Can't say them, such strong words
少しだけ 静かにしてほしいね
I'd like it to be just a little bit quieter
あぁ 私たち 待望へ
Ah, towards our long-awaited goal
世界 テテテ 降伏やいや
World, te-te-te, surrender, no no
果たせ その日まで
Carry it out, until that day
ネネネ 降伏やいや
Ne-ne-ne, surrender, no no
あなたの周りも ヨヨヨ
Around you too, yo-yo-yo
警戒 セセセ 降伏あれあらあ
Caution, se-se-se, surrender, oh my oh my
約束の地まで
Until the promised land
さあ 掲げよう バッテン バッテン
Now, let's raise it, X mark, X mark
デンデン 降伏やいや
Den-den, surrender, no no
今日も 嫌い そっちのけだね
Hating it today too, putting it aside
嫌になるから 私一人でも
Because I'm getting sick of it, even if I'm alone
やっていくわ
I'll keep going
...行きますよね
...will go, won't it?
すべて すべて すべて任せて
Leave everything, everything, everything to me.
それをさせてよ 大事なことなの
Let me do it, it's important.
わかっているでしょう
You understand, right?
四六時中 会いに行くの
I'll go see you twenty-four-seven.
会えない めんどくさいまま 今日も明日も 過ぎてゆくのでしょう
Unable to meet, in this annoying state, today and tomorrow will surely pass by.
仮面に水を上げましょう
Let's give water to the mask.
時計の中 枯れたこと忘れてた
Inside the clock, I'd forgotten it had withered.
さあ ダダダ 黙れ 黙り給えよ
Now, s-s-s-shut up, shut your mouth.
言えないね そんな強い言葉は
I can't say it, such strong words.
少しだけ 静かにしてほしい ああ
I just want it to be a little quiet, ah.
私たち 退屈
We're bored.
今と未来 見たかったはずなのに
Even though we were supposed to want to see the present and the future.
世界転々プクヤイヤイ 見えぬその日まで
The world's changing, puku-yai-yai, until that day we cannot see.
ドドド エーエー この世のことわり ヨヨヨイ
Do-do-do, eh-eh, the truth of this world, yo-yo-yoi.
今 ゼンゼンブクサササ あなたの街中
Now, zen-zen-buku-sa-sa-sa, in the middle of your town.
かたち作るはバッテン 世界転々プクヤイヤイ
Forming an X, the world's changing, puku-yai-yai.
果てぬその日まで ネネネコプクヤイヤイ
Until that endless day, ne-ne-neko-puku-yai-yai.
あなたの周りも ヨヨヨイ 限界ゼンゼンハクアレアレア
Around you too, yo-yo-yoi, the limit is zen-zen-haku-are-are-a.
約束の地まで さあ掲げよバッテン
To the promised land, now hold up the X.
バッテンバッテンブクシラリン 天使のワインを開けましょう
X, X, buku-shirarin, let's open the angel's wine.
さあみんな 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Now everyone, thank you for coming!
続けて歌うので 盛り上がっていきましょう！
I'll keep singing, so let's get hyped!
声出せー！
Give me some noise!
音楽 すりぃ 歌 鷹嶺ルイ
Music: Three / Vocal: Takane Lui
腐りかけた心にI need you 噂のアルカロイド
To a heart on the verge of rot, I need you, the rumored alkaloid.
エゴロック 作詞・作曲：すりぃ
Ego Rock / Lyrics & Composition: Three
あだ名はネットのしゃれこうべ 掻き鳴らせディストーション
Nicknamed the web's skull, strum that distortion.
付け焼き刃の侍が 乱れ打つ三段銃
A makeshift samurai firing off a three-shot gun.
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか ほら てんてこへんてこまいまい
Shall we dance in a history of tragedy? Look, it's a frantic, hectic mess.
「はあ？」 僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度のナンセンス
"Huh?" My heart is Ego Rock, a 45-degree angle of nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crush the know-how, say bye-bye-bye to the rut tomorrow.
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning figure of yours, it's a nauseating sky.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
A rain of cynical stares, pretending to cover both eyes again today.
もっともっと声出せるでしょ！ 皆さん 行きますよ！
You can give me even more noise! Everyone, here we go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
おちゃらけ頭にI need you 巷のアルカロイド
To a joking head, I need you, the street's alkaloid.
あの子も流行りのインスタントショー 巻き散らせVIP
That girl's also a trendy instant show, scatter that VIP status.
うだつが上がらぬ侍が 未来断つ愛とか
A samurai who never catches a break, with love that cuts off the future.
無残な歴史で歌おうぜ ほら ちゃんちゃらなんちゃらまいまい
Let's sing in a cruel history, look, it's a ridiculous, silly mess.
「はあ？」 ロックな心で生きようか 真夏並みホットなミュージック
"Huh?" Shall we live with a rock heart? Music as hot as midsummer.
恥を砕いて丸書いて 明日もワハハ
Crush the shame, draw a circle, and laugh tomorrow too.
ちゃれくささも癖になる はみ出し者だろう
This playfulness becomes a habit, you're an outcast, right?
リリカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を開くふり
A rain of lyrical stares, pretending to open both eyes again today.
透明な感情は 染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions just get dyed.
だったら見て見ぬふりする 奴らを押し出せ
In that case, push out the ones who pretend not to see.
人生かけても負けそうです 勝ち負け取り憑かれナンセンス
Even if I bet my life, I'd probably lose; obsessed with winning or losing, it's nonsense.
1分砕いて常識を 未来にセーグッバイ
Crush common sense for a minute, say goodbye to the future.
僕の心はエゴロック 斜め45度のナンセンス
My heart is Ego Rock, a 45-degree angle of nonsense.
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを 明日にバイバイバイ
Crush the know-how, say bye-bye-bye to the rut tomorrow.
媚びへつらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
That fawning figure of yours, it's a nauseating sky.
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
A rain of cynical stares, pretending to cover both eyes again today.
One, two, three, fuck you!
コールボーイ
作詞・作曲：syudou
Call Boy
Lyrics/Composition: syudou
半額一か八かのバー　凡庸な色取り自称非凡人
A half-priced hit-or-miss bar, mediocre colors for a self-proclaimed extraordinary person
使い捨てしたいクズと　されたい輩で大繁盛
Thriving with trash who want to use others, and those who want to be used
混ぜ物の目の安価なバボ　半端な貴方がよく似合う
Cheap bubbles with mixed eyes, they suit half-baked you perfectly
よだれも同じ事なんてのが　お決まりなんだけど
Even drooling the same thing is common, but...
人は孤独を殺すため　虚しさを燃やすため
People drink to kill their loneliness, to burn away the emptiness
酒を飲むんだ
They drink alcohol
金も時間も感情も　なんでもやるからさ
Money, time, even emotions, I'll give you everything
二人で酔いよ
Let's get drunk together
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に
俺には一切記憶がねぇんだよ
Before even saying if it's good or bad
I have no memory of it at all
明日もまた　猛弁解
Tomorrow again, a fierce excuse
飲んだら明日に響くと云うけど
飲まなきゃその明日すらもねぇんだよ
They say if I drink it'll affect tomorrow
But if I don't drink, that tomorrow won't even exist
嫌になるぜ　もう一杯
DON'T STOP!
I'm sick of this, another glass
構わずにもう一杯
Without a care, another glass
明日行方今夜の便も　全部失くしてなお大繁盛
Even after losing tomorrow's whereabouts and tonight's mail, business is booming
プライド取り捨て助平　愛を偽るのは簡単だ
Throwing away pride, a lecher, it's easy to fake love
人差し指で黙らして　一箇所略語前二神
Silencing with a forefinger, one place abbreviated, the former two gods
結局いつもの事と　山ほどお仕舞なんだけど
In the end, it's just the usual thing, and a mountain of ends, but...
人は誰もが偽善者さ　優しい嘘を餌に
Everyone is a hypocrite, using kind lies as bait
狩りをするんだ
To go hunting
血酒日の酒苦い酒　ねぇ優しくするからさ
Blood sake, sun sake, bitter sake, hey, I'll be kind to you
一人は嫌だ
I hate being alone
愛だの恋だのやんやと騒ぐが
酔ったら結局誰でもいいんだよ
They make a fuss about love and romance
But when they're drunk, anyone will do
荒ぶりて　暴言タイム
Getting rowdy, verbal abuse time
その「誰でも」すら俺は選ばれず
泣くのもだせぇし酒を浴びんだよ
Even as that "anyone," I am not chosen
Crying is uncool, so I'll drench myself in alcohol
嫌になるぜ　もう一杯
CAN'T STOP!
I'm sick of this, another glass
意味も無くもう一杯
Without any meaning, another glass
馬鹿と煙が梯子酒　昇る様はさながら蜘蛛の糸
Fools and smoke bar-hop together, their ascent is like a spider's thread
どこもかしこもクソだらけ　おい一番クソなのは
Everywhere is full of shit, hey, the shittiest thing is...
お前だ馬鹿
...you, you idiot
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に
俺には一切記憶がねぇんだよ
Before even saying if it's good or bad
I have no memory of it at all
嫌になるぜ　もう限界
I'm sick of this, I'm at my limit
飲んでもないのに難なく生きてる
アンタの方こそ呑まれてるんだよ
Even without drinking, you're living effortlessly
You're the one who's truly swallowed up
嫌になるぜ　もう一杯
WONT STOP
I'm sick of this, another glass
死ぬ前にもう一杯
Before I die, another glass
はい、連続で3曲聞いていただきましたけど
Yes, you've just heard three songs in a row
いかがでしょうか？かっこよかった？
How was it? Was it cool?
お、コメントが流れてたな。
Oh, the comments were flying by.
おお、かっこいい！嬉しい。かっこよかった。ありがとうございます。
Oh, "cool"! I'm happy. "It was cool". Thank you very much.
今日もね、見に来てくださってありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to watch today as well.
ツイートね、こちらのハッシュタグ
For tweets, please use this hashtag...
「#鷹嶺ルイ1周年LIVE」でね、呟いてくれると嬉しいです。
..."#鷹嶺ルイ1周年LIVE". I'd be happy if you'd tweet with it.
ということで、凄く緊張しているんだけれども...
So, I'm very nervous, but...
おや？ちょっと見てくださいよ。このステージ。
Oh? Please take a look at this stage.
鷹嶺ルイの特別仕様にしていただきましたー！
It's been made into a special Takane Lui version!
コラボするのは初めてなので
Since this is our first collaboration,
ちょっと楽しみにしていただき
please look forward to it,
最後には重大発表もありますので
and there's a major announcement at the end, so
最後まで楽しんでってください！
please enjoy until the end!
それでは、準備にレッツゴー！
Well then, let's go get ready!
Hate...
You...
いじぬっ子 Bully
作詞・作曲：Calliope Mori
Bully
Lyrics & Composition: Calliope Mori
Dress up and diamond dance, A la mode decay
Call me "sis," sorry "sis," what more can I say?
踏みつけた蟻の 行列なんて
Like a line of ants that I've stepped on,
お嬢さん 西の国から
Miss, from the western country,
愛の為に
For the sake of love...
貴方に会いに来ました
I have come to meet you.
急な話ですがどうか驚かないで
It's sudden, but please don't be surprised.
僕のお姫様にね なって下さい
Please, become my princess.
悩んでるのお嬢さん
Are you troubled, miss?
浮かない顔は
That gloomy face...
似合わないよほらほら 耳を貸してよ
Doesn't suit you, look, lend me your ear.
もしもしよろしければですが
If you'd like, if I may...
俺と一緒に全て捨てて逃げよう
Throw everything away and run away with me.
東の国へ
To the eastern country.
寂しそうなその
On those lonely-looking...
赤い唇に
Red lips...
優しい魔法かけるよ
I'll cast a gentle spell.
さあさあドレスに着替えて
Now, now, change into your dress,
世界一のお姫様
The number one princess in the world.
踊りましょうか?
Shall we dance?
誰もが貴方を欲しがって
Everyone wants you,
僕らを夢中にさせちゃって
You've got us captivated.
奪うよ 愛のKISS
I'll steal it, a kiss of love.
瞳閉じてプレゼント
Close your eyes for a present,
空に光るあの星を
That star shining in the sky,
二人のものに
Will belong to the two of us.
世界が貴方を欲しがって
The world wants you,
俺たち本気にさせちゃって
You've made us get serious,
その名はジュリエッタ
Her name is Julietta.
命に代えても 守り抜いてみせます
I'll show you I can protect you even if it costs my life.
さあ おいで
Now, come here.
後悔はさせない 色褪せない景色へ
I won't let you regret it, to a scenery that never fades.
さあ おいで
Now, come here.
選んで!
Choose!
渡したくない 他の誰かには
I don't want to hand you over to anyone else.
譲れないのさ 誰にも
I won't give you up to anyone.
さあ裸足で駆け出せ
Now, run out barefoot,
世界一のお姫様
The number one princess in the world.
夢の世界へ
To a dream world.
不安な思いは消し去って
Erase those anxious thoughts,
ちょっぴりルール破っちゃって
Break the rules just a little bit,
狙うよ 愛のKISS
I'm aiming for it, a kiss of love.
手を繋いで連れてくよ
I'll hold your hand and take you away,
海に眠る宝石を
The jewels sleeping in the sea,
二人のものに
Will belong to the two of us.
世界が貴方を欲しがって
The world wants you,
僕らを本気にさせちゃって
You've made us get serious,
その名はジュリエッタ
Her name is Julietta.
貴方のことしか見えなくて
I can only see you,
僕らの本気を見せちゃって
We'll show you how serious we are,
その名はジュリエッタ
Her name is Julietta.
Yeah!
あんたにゃ もったいない
You're too good for him,
あたしは本当 ナイスバディバディバディ
I really have a nice body, body, body.
自分で 言うくらい
I'm even saying it myself,
タダじゃないじゃないかな
I'm not just ordinary, am I?
熱けりゃ 冷ませばいい
If it's hot, just let it cool,
寂しけりゃ エブリバディバディバディ
If you're lonely, everybody, body, body.
誰にも 負けない
I won't lose to anyone,
恋愛って いつ火がつくのか ダイナマイト
When will love catch fire? Dynamite.
恋はダイナマイト
Love is dynamite.
どんなに 酷くたって
No matter how terrible it is,
恋はインフレーション
Love is inflation.
こんなに 優しくされちゃ
Being treated this kindly,
ダイヤ
Diamond.
明るい 未来に
To a bright future,
就職希望だわ
I want to be employed.
日本の未来は
Japan's future is...
Wow Wow Wow Wow
世界がうらやむ
The world envies it.
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
恋をしようじゃないか！
Let's fall in love!
Wow Wow Wow Wow
Dancin' all of the night
なんだか 物足りない
I'm feeling somewhat unsatisfied
どこにいたって愛してほしいわ
I want to be loved no matter where I am
自分で伝えるの
I'll say it myself
恥ずかしくないじゃない
It's not embarrassing at all
ない！
No!
理想な Wonderful World
An ideal wonderful world
憧れよ Everybody Body Body
Something everyone longs for
誰しも気づいてない
Nobody has realized it yet
恋愛って夢の落とし穴
Romance is a dream's pitfall
Mystery
恋は Mystery
Love is a mystery
そんなの不自然だって
Saying that's unnatural...
恋のインサイダー
Is being a love insider
それでも上手にされちゃ
Even so, if I'm handled well...
Ah Love Wow
幸せ この日も
I'm happy on this day too
キャンセル待ちなの
Waiting on the cancellation list
Wow Wow Wow Wow
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile...
Wow Wow Wow Wow
世界がうらやむ
Is the envy of the world
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
夢があるんじゃないか！
There's a dream, isn't there!
Wow Wow Wow Wow
Dance!
Dancin' all of the night
Love Love Love Machine
Love Love Love Station
Love Love Love Factory
Love Is So Wonderful
Yeah!
日本の未来は
Japan's future...
Wow Wow Wow Wow
世界がうらやむ
Is the envy of the world
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
恋をしようじゃないか！
Let's fall in love!
Wow Wow Wow Wow
Dancin' all of the night
モーニング娘。も
Morning Musume too...
Wow Wow Wow Wow
あんたもあたしも
Both you and I
Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
みんなも社長さんも
Everyone, even the boss
Wow Wow Wow Wow
Dance!
Dancin' all of the night
LOVE Machine.
Oh Up Side Down
回る回るよ 感情車 風切る羽根が踊ってる
Spinning, spinning, carriage of emotions, wind-cutting wings are dancing
早く走って スピード出せば ピンクになって 波動車
Run fast, if you pick up speed, it turns pink, a wave carriage
七転び八起き
Ups and downs
希望が奮い 絶望
Hope rouses, then despair
そこから そこから
From there, from there...
這い上がってみせろよ
Show me how you crawl back up
回る回るよ人生なんて ジェットコースターみたいさ
Turning, turning, life is just like a roller coaster
形勢不利も 次のカーブで 見事にどんでん返し
Even if you're at a disadvantage, the next curve will bring a total reversal
七転び八起き
Ups and downs
最後がどうやら 肝心
The ending is what matters
冷静沈着
Calm and collected
突破の器
The vessel for a breakthrough
回り道でも たどり着ければいいじゃない
Even if it's a detour, isn't it fine if you get there?
最後の最後に 笑えば
As long as you laugh at the very end
明日のことよりも 今日が大事
Today is more important than tomorrow
バカなふり ばっかりしてるヤツが
The guy who's always playing the fool
いいヤツだったりするんだ
Might actually be a good guy
七回目 転んだら
If you fall for the seventh time
One more time!
次がチャンスだよ！
The next one is your chance!
Oh Up Side Down
七転び八起き
Seven Falls, Eight Rises
僕は　僕は
I am, I am...
生きているよね
...alive, right?
自己主張するのはいいけど
Asserting yourself is fine, but...
むせる気持ち
A choking feeling,
料理の女神
The goddess of cooking
目の前通るの掴め
Grab what passes before your eyes
七転び八起き
Fall seven times, stand up eight
最後がどええ感じ
The end feels great
万丈一致で
With unanimous agreement,
君に軍配
The victory goes to you
遠回り道でも
Even if it's a detour,
たどり着ければいいじゃない
it's fine as long as we get there
最後の最後に笑えば
If we smile at the very end
明日（あした）のことよりも
Rather than tomorrow,
今が大事
now is what's important
ジョークばっかり言ってるアイツが
That guy who's always telling jokes
信用できたりするんだ
might actually be trustworthy
八回目　起き上がれ
The eighth time, get back up
One more time!
今がチャンスだよ！
Now is your chance!
遠回り道でも
Even if it's a detour,
たどり着ければいいじゃない
it's fine as long as we get there
最後の最後に笑えば
If we smile at the very end
明日（あした）のことよりも
Rather than tomorrow,
今日が大事
today is what's important
バカなふりばっかりしてるヤツが
The one who's always playing the fool
いいヤツだったりするんだ
might actually be a good guy
七回目　転んだら
The seventh time you fall,
One more time!
次がチャンスだよ！
Next time is your chance!
七転び八起き
Fall seven times, stand up eight
制服のマネキン
作詞：秋元康　作曲：杉山勝彦
Seifuku no Mannequin
Lyrics: Yasushi Akimoto / Music: Katsuhiko Sugiyama
君が...
What you...
目を追いかけて
Chasing your eyes
低気圧過ぎる交差点
At the intersection with too much low pressure
動く唇 呼んでみたけど
I tried calling your moving lips, but...
YESかNOか
YES or NO
河川敷の野球場で
At the baseball field on the riverbed
ボールを打った金属音
The metallic sound of hitting a ball
黙り込んだ 僕らの所へ
To where we fell silent
飛んでくればいい
It should just fly over
一歩目を踏み出してみなきゃ
You have to take the first step
何も始まらないよ
Or nothing will start
頭の中で 答えを出すな
Don't give an answer inside your head
恋をするのはいけないことか
Is falling in love a bad thing?
僕の懐に飛び込めよ
Jump into my arms
若すぎる それだけで
Being too young, just for that
大人に邪魔をさせない
Don't let adults get in the way
恋をするのはいけないことか
Is falling in love a bad thing?
君の気持ちはわかってる
I know how you feel
感情を隠したら
If you hide your emotions
制服を着たマネキンだ
You're just a mannequin in a uniform
冬型の気圧配置に
In the winter pressure pattern
心が冷え込みそうだよ
My heart feels like it's freezing
自販機の缶コーヒー
A canned coffee from a vending machine
君の手にあげる
I'll give it to your hand
卒業を待ってみたところで
Even if we wait for graduation
何も変わらないだろう
Nothing will probably change
今しかできない チョイスもあるさ
There are choices you can only make now
どんな自分を守ってるのか
What kind of self are you protecting?
純情の壁 壊すんだ
Break down the wall of pure heart
汚れなきものなんて
Something pure and stainless
大人が求める幻想
Is just a fantasy that adults seek
どんな自分を守ってるのか
What kind of self are you protecting?
僕は本気で好きなんだ
I truly love you
その意思はどこにある
Where is that will located?
制服を着たマネキンよ
Oh, mannequin in a uniform
できないんじゃない
It's not that you can't
やってないだけさ
It's just that you aren't doing it
未来の扉
The door to the future
そこにあるのに
Even though it's right there
僕は何度も誘おう
I will invite you many times
生まれ変わるのは君だ
The one who will be reborn is you
僕にまかせろ
Leave it to me
恋をするのはいけないことか
Is falling in love a bad thing?
僕の懐に飛び込めよ
Jump into my arms
若すぎる それだけで
Being too young, just for that
大人に邪魔をさせない
Don't let adults get in the way
恋をするのはいけないことか
Is falling in love a bad thing?
君の気持ちはわかってる
I know how you feel
感情を隠したら
If you hide your emotions
制服を着たマネキンだ
You're just a mannequin in a uniform
交差点の途中で不安になる
In the middle of an intersection, I become anxious
あの信号 いつまで青い色なんだろう？
How long will that traffic light stay green?
ふいに点滅し始め 急かすのかな
Does it suddenly start flashing to hurry me up?
Suddenly starting to blink, is it rushing me?
いつの間にか少し 早歩きになってた
Without realizing it, I've started walking a bit faster.
自分の意思 関係ないように
As if my own will has nothing to do with it.
誰も彼もみんな 一斉に走り出す
Everyone, one and all, starts running at once.
何に追われ焦るのかと笑う
I laugh, wondering what they're being chased by to be in such a hurry.
客観的に見てる私が 嫌いだ
I hate myself for watching so objectively.
決心のきっかけは 理屈ではなくて
The motivation for a decision isn't logic.
いつだってこの胸の衝動から始まる
It always starts from an impulse in my chest.
流されてしまうこと 抵抗しながら
While resisting being swept away...
生きるとは選択肢 たった一つを選ぶこと
To live is to choose just one option.
横断歩道 渡っていつも思う
I always think while crossing the crosswalk.
こんな風に心に信号があればいい
I wish there were traffic lights in the heart like this.
進みなさい それから 止まりなさい
"Go ahead," and then, "Stop."
それがルールならば 悩まずに行けるけれど…
If those were the rules, I could go without worrying, but...
誰かの指示 待ち続けたくない
I don't want to keep waiting for someone's instructions.
走りたい時に 自分で踏み出せる
To be able to step out on my own when I want to run.
強い意志を持った人でいたい
I want to be a person with a strong will.
もう一人の明日の私を 探そう
Let's find the another me of tomorrow.
決心のきっかけは 時間切れじゃなくて
The motivation for a decision isn't running out of time.
考えたその上で未来を信じること
It's about believing in the future after thinking it through.
後悔はしたくない 思ったそのまま
I don't want to have regrets, just as I thought.
正解はわからない たった一度の人生だ
I don't know the right answer, it's my only life.
ほら人ごみの誰かが走り出す
Look, someone in the crowd starts running.
釣られたみたいにみんなが走り出す
As if lured, everyone starts running.
自分のこと 自分で決められず
Unable to decide my own matters for myself,
背中を押すもの 欲しいんだ
I want something to push me forward.
きっかけ
Motivation.
決心のきっかけは 理屈ではなくて
The motivation for a decision isn't logic.
いつだってこの胸の衝動から始まる
It always starts from an impulse in my chest.
流されてしまうこと 抵抗しながら
While resisting being swept away...
生きるとは選択肢 たった一つを選ぶこと
To live is to choose just one option.
決心は自分から 思ったそのまま…
The decision comes from within, just as I thought...
生きよう
Let's live.
はい。ということで、「きっかけ」聴いていただきました。
Okay. And with that, you've heard "Kikkake".
「きっかけ」の途中に…
In the middle of "Kikkake"...
わあ、なんと！憧れのホロライブのアイドル衣装をいただくことができ、着させていただきました。
Wow, look! I was able to receive the Hololive idol costume I admired, and I've put it on.
どう？どう？似合う？
How is it? Does it suit me?
似合う？可愛い？
Does it look good? Is it cute?
自分でもね、似合うかなって、凄く不安だったんだけれども…
I was actually really worried whether it would suit me, but...
色々ね、
We talked about many things...
あの、こうした方がいいんじゃない、あした方がいいんじゃないってちょっと
...like how we should do this, or maybe that.
相談をさせていただき、
After consulting with everyone...
こういったね私に似合う衣装を
...I was able to receive this outfit...
頂くことができました。
...that suits me so well.
これもね、みんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます。
This is all thanks to you. Thank you so much.
そしてね、えー...はぁ、なんか緊張しちゃってる、まだ。(笑)
And also... phew, I'm still feeling a bit nervous. (Laughs)
えー、コラボパート、歌わせて頂いたんですが、みんなといかがでしたか？
I sang the collaboration part, but how was it with everyone?
お、めちゃ良かったかな？
Oh, was it really good?
実は、まぁたくさんね、喋りたいんだけど、ちょっとね尺の方がもうそろそろやばいということで、
Actually, there's so much I want to talk about, but time is running out...
完結にお話をすると、あのね、さっきの『きっかけ』と、
...so to put it simply, the songs "Kikkake" and...
なんか『制服のマネキン』っていうのが私の大好きな乃木坂46さんの曲なんですよ。
..."Seifuku no Mannequin" are songs by Nogizaka46, who I love.
で、作曲者さんが私一回ねラジオとかでもお話ししたことがあるんだけど、
And the composer, as I've mentioned on the radio before,
杉山勝彦さんという私の憧れのね作曲者さんが、
is Katsuhiko Sugiyama-san, a composer I've always admired.
あの、作った曲でして、私がすごく大好きな2曲だったので、今回歌わせて頂きました。
He created those songs, and since they're two of my favorites, I sang them today.
そして次の曲が最後になるんですけれども、
And the next song will be the last one.
実はその最後の曲、えー、今回、初披露となるオリジナル曲になります。
This last song will be an original song that I'm performing for the first time.
そしてその曲が、実は杉山勝彦さんに書き下ろして頂きました。
And this song was actually written for me by Katsuhiko Sugiyama-san.
そしてですね、わっ「そして、そして」ってめちゃくちゃ多いんだけど。(笑)
And also... wow, I'm saying "and also" a lot. (Laughs)
えー、作詞をですね、私、鷹嶺ルイが、杉山さんと一緒に作らせて頂きました。
I, Takane Lui, co-wrote the lyrics with Sugiyama-san.
作詞させて頂きました。
I wrote the lyrics for it.
この曲はね、あのルイ友さん、いつも応援してくださってるルイ友さんに贈るプレゼントになっていますので、
This song is a gift for my Lui-tomo who always support me.
ちょっと、まぁ、まぁとりあえず聴いてくれよ。(笑)
So, well, just listen to it first. (Laughs)
聴いてくれたら、「あ、こういう気持ちで書いたのかな」っていうのがすごく、
If you listen, you might feel the emotions I put into writing it...
なんだろう、ストレートに伝わってくる曲に仕上がったと思うので、
...it turned out to be a very straightforward song.
ぜひ、ちょっと聴いて頂けたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could give it a listen.
それでは、聴いてください。
Please listen.
TSUBASA
作詞：鷹嶺ルイ、杉山勝彦
作曲：杉山勝彦
TSUBASA
Lyrics: Takane Lui, Katsuhiko Sugiyama
Composition: Katsuhiko Sugiyama
大丈夫？泣かないで
Are you okay? Don't cry.
私がいつもついてるよ
I'll always be by your side.
辛いのを隠しがちな君
You, who tends to hide your pain...
放っておけないよ
I can't just leave you alone.
大丈夫　泣かないで
It's okay, don't cry.
でも無理に笑わないで
But don't force a smile, either.
ゆっくり空見上げてよう
Let's slowly look up at the sky.
似た者同士で
Since we're two of a kind.
翼を傷めた君　今度は私が支えるから
You with the hurt wings, this time I'll support you.
消えかけた夢に涙した日もあったけれど
There were days I cried over fading dreams.
君の言う“大丈夫”で諦めずに来れた
But thanks to your "It's okay," I could keep going.
まだ遅くないよ　ここから始まるストーリー
It's not too late. The story begins here.
さあ少し休んで
Now, take a little rest.
涙を拭いて歩きだそう
Wipe your tears and let's start walking.
覚えてる？私もね　折れかけた翼抱いて
Remember? I was also holding onto broken wings.
励ます君に甘えてた
Relying on you while you cheered me on.
ほらあの日のこと
Look back at that day.
雨上がりの刹那に　私たちは強く生まれ変わる
In the moment after the rain, we're reborn strong.
心無い声に耳をふさぐ日もあるけれど
Some days we shut out heartless voices.
味方がここにいる
But an ally is right here.
手当ては任せてよ
Leave the healing to me.
また増えてゆくよ　これから叶えるストーリー
They'll keep growing, the stories we'll fulfill.
さあ手を取り合って
Now, let's take each other's hands.
遥か彼方を見つめよう
And look toward the far horizon.
これから先は傷つかずには進めない
From now on, we can't move forward without getting hurt.
だけど覚えてて
But please remember...
君はもう一人じゃないから胸を張って
...you're not alone anymore, so hold your head high.
私たち今も不器用で無邪気な小鳥
We're still clumsy and innocent little birds.
譲れない夢抱いて
Holding onto dreams we won't give up.
翼はためかせよう　大空へ…
Let's flap our wings to the wide sky...
向かい風受けて高く高く飛び立とう
Facing the headwind, let's fly high, high up.
向かい風受けて 高く高く飛び立とう
Facing the headwind, let's fly high, high up
また雨が降り出しても
Even if it starts raining again
私が守るから
I will protect you
この先にどんな未来が待ってるか分からない
I don't know what kind of future lies ahead
だけど信じている
But I believe
君とならどこまでもいける
With you, I can go anywhere
一緒に見る夢のストーリー
The story of the dream we see together
この後24時から 先ほど披露いたしました、
From 24:00 tonight, the song I just performed,
鷹嶺ルイ2つ目のオリジナル曲、「TSUBASA」が
各種音楽サイトよりリリースされます。
Takane Lui's 2nd original song 'TSUBASA',
will be released on various music platforms.
私が憧れておりました数々の乃木坂46
It was composed by Katsuhiko Sugiyama,
名楽曲を作成した、杉山勝彦さんに
作っていただきました。
who created many of the Nogizaka46 masterpieces
that I've always admired.
作詞には今回私も参加させていただいております。
I also participated in writing the lyrics this time.
みんな悩みや葛藤はあるけれども、
The lyrics are positive, saying that although
一緒に手を取って進んでいこうね、
という前向きな歌詞になっております。
everyone has worries, let's take each other's
hands and move forward.
私からルイ友さんへの日頃の感謝を込めて
作詞をしたので、
I wrote the lyrics with daily gratitude
for the Lui-tomo,
ぜひぜひたくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be very happy if you'd listen to it a lot.
ミュージックビデオは現在鋭意作成中です。
The music video is currently in the works.
こだわって作成しているので、
We're creating it with great care,
少しお時間はいただきますが、楽しみにしてて下さい。
so it will take a little time, but look forward to it.
そしてそして！この後私のチャンネルで、
And! Right after this on my channel,
ライブでも歌いました「エゴロック」を
公開いたします。
I will release 'Ego Rock,' which I also sang
during the live.
歌動画を1年、毎月欠かさず上げられたのは
I was able to upload music videos every month
皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとう！
for a year thanks to all of you. Thank you so much!
これからも歌も頑張るの、楽しみにしてて下さいね。
I'll continue to do my best with singing,
so please look forward to it.
鷹嶺ルイ、1周年、おめでとうー！
Takane Lui, 1st Anniversary, Congratulations!
ありがとうございます、今日来てくれて！
Thank you for coming today!
「LOVEマシーン」歌えてよかった、
2人と...あ、3人で！
I'm glad we could sing 'LOVE Machine' together
with the two of... ah, three of us!
私ね、辻ちゃんだったの。
I was Tsuji-chan.
あ、気づいた？じゃあ、じゃあ私が
加護ちゃん、加護ちゃんで！
Ah, did you notice? Then, then I'll be
Kago-chan, Kago-chan!
ミニモニ、ミニモニ。デカモニ、デカモニ。
Minimoni, Minimoni. Dekamoni, Dekamoni.
まりんくらい小さくなってから出直してきてください。
Please come back after getting as small as Marine.
いろんな意味でデカモニなんで、じゃあさよならー。
I'm Dekamoni in many ways, so goodbye!
鷹嶺ルイ、おめでとう。
Takane Lui, congratulations.
え、あ、ありがとうございます。
なんかどうしたんですかそんなカッコつけて。
Eh, ah, thank you.
Why are you acting so cool all of a sudden?
鷹嶺ルイ、結婚しよう。
Takane Lui, let's get married.
いや結婚はしないけど、なんかありがとう。
No, I won't marry you, but thanks.
いやね、なんかね、みんな、なんかちょっと、
大変だったよねこれね。
You know, everyone, it was a bit of a struggle,
wasn't it?
この同期でできてよかった、同期3人で！
I'm glad we could do this as Genmates, the three of us!
最高！4期生！愛ゆえのイジり、愛ゆえのイジり。
Awesome! 4th Gen! Teasing out of love, teasing out of love.
いやでも本当この3人でね、なんか6人の
But really, being able to do the 6-person
フォーメーションだったりとか
フォーメーションダンスできて、
formations and formation dancing
with just the three of us,
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです。ありがとうございました！
made me so happy. Thank you so much!
楽しんでいただけたんじゃないでしょうかということで、
明後日はクロエ。頑張るよ！
I hope everyone enjoyed it. So, the day after
tomorrow is Chloe. Good luck!
はーい、おめでとう！それなりに頑張りまーす。
Okay, congrats! I'll do my best in my own way.
ルイルイ、1周年、おめでとうー！
Lui-Lui, 1st Anniversary, Congratulations!
ありがとうございます、来てくれて嬉しい、嬉しい！
Thank you, I'm so happy you came!
いやかっこよくね、歌えましたね。「LOVEマシーン」。
一緒に歌いたかったんですよ。
Yeah, we sang it coolly. 'LOVE Machine'.
I've always wanted to sing it together.
なんで？ なぜこの3人でセットなんの？
Why? Why are we a set of three?
Special Thanks: 日南めい, KosK, 宮内椋太, 犬絵, 芝山 武憲
Special Thanks: Hinami Mei, KosK, Miyauchi Ryota, Inu-e, Shibayama Takenori
あ、そう？
Oh, really?
なんとなくこの3人がいいかな？ みたいな...
I just thought these three would be good... sort of...
なんとなくなんでんすね。
So it's just "somehow."
はい、なんとなく。なんとなくです。
Yes, somehow. It's just somehow.
ここで似合うと思ってたよね？
We thought it'd suit us here, right?
Special Thanks: Symny, まつこ, クリスP, よつやちゃん
Special Thanks: Symny, Matsuko, Chris P, Yotsuya-chan
うーん、ちょっとね、期待して来たんだよね。
Yeah, I came here looking forward to it a bit.
ちょっと来年...
Maybe next year...
あ、じゃ、来年なんとなくまた呼んでもらえたら...
Oh, well, if I can have you back somehow next year...
Special Thanks: 快晴P
Special Thanks: Kaisei P
あ、来てくれるんですか？ なんとなく。
Oh, will you come? Somehow.
なんとなく来る。
I'll come somehow.
なんとなくOKしてくれる。
They'll give a "somehow OK."
なんとなく来ます。
I'll come somehow.
じゃ、また来年もよろしくお願いいたします！
Well, please look forward to next year too!
...and You!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please do!
じゃ、なんとなく招き猫ポーズして終わりにしましょう。
Well, let's end with a "somehow" maneki-neko pose.
あ、いいよ。
Oh, okay.
せーの！
One, two!
ルイ友のみんなへ！！ みんなのおかげで1周年をむかえることが出来ました☆
To all Lui-tomo!! Thanks to everyone, I reached my 1st anniversary☆
本当にいつも応援ありがとう♡ こうやって歌に配信に全力でいられるのはルイ友のみんながいるから！！
Thank you for the support♡ I can sing and stream with all my might because you're here!!
器用そうにみえて、実は超不器用な私だけど……
I might look capable, but I'm actually super clumsy...
これからも“夢”に向かって羽ばたき続けるから、ずっと見守ってネ♡ 大スキ♡
I'll keep flying toward my "dreams," so please keep watching over me♡ Love you♡
はい、ここで1周年記念のオリジナルグッズの紹介をさせていただきます！ ドン！
Okay, I'd like to introduce the 1st anniversary original goods here! Boom!
はい、ということで今回はですね、「おうちデート」をテーマにですね、作らせていただきました。
Yes, so this time, we made them with the theme of a "Home Date."
もうすでに可愛い、この画像だけでね。
It's already cute, just from this image.
ということで一つ一つ紹介していきましょう。まずは、こちら。
So, let's introduce them one by one. First, this one.
MAIRO先生描き下ろしの2層アクリルパネルになっております。
This is a 2-layer acrylic panel drawn by MAIRO-sensei.
私のね、大好きなMAIRO先生に描いていただきました。
It was drawn by MAIRO-sensei, whom I love.
こちらを飾ってね、ちょっとルイと一緒に過ごしてるみたいな妄想していただけたらなと思うんですけれども。
I hope you can display this and imagine you're spending time with Lui.
ま、そういう妄想にはね、温かい飲み物が必須ということで、続いてはこちら。
Well, for such imaginings, a warm drink is a must, so next is this.
トウミ先生描き下ろしのルイとお揃いタンブラーもね、今回発売させていただきます。
We're also selling a tumbler that matches Lui's, drawn by Toumi-sensei.
いや、めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
Wow, it's super cute.
ここにね、温かいお茶を入れて、ちょっと先ほどね、アクリルパネルを見ながら
I hope you can put warm tea in here and, while looking at the acrylic panel,
ちょっとしっぽりとね、妄想していただければなと思うんですけれども。
enjoy your imagination quietly.
続いて、大目玉商品、こちら！
Next, the main attraction, this!
ふわもち♡つくね＆つみれクッションということで、
The "Fuwamochi♡ Tsukune & Tsumire Cushion."
肌触りにもすごくこだわったクッションになっておりまして、ふわふわもちもちってするのでね。
We were very particular about the texture; it's fluffy and squishy.
ぜひ抱きしめてもちもちと過ごしてください。
Please hold it tight and enjoy its squishiness.
いや、こういうクッションは何個あってもいいですからね。はい。
You can never have too many cushions like this. Yes.
で、今回もルイ描き下ろしシナリオのボイスも販売しております。
And we're also selling voice packs with scenarios written by Lui.
全部すべて買っていただきますと、特別にえー、ポストカードがついてまいります。
If you buy the full set, you'll get a special bonus postcard.
前回ねお誕生日の時には直筆サインだったんですけれども、
Last time for my birthday, it was a handwritten signature,
今回は箔押しサインで直筆メッセージをつけまして、お送りさせていただきます。
but this time it's a foil-stamped signature with a handwritten message.
今回も無制限なのでゆっくりとね、何買おうかなって...
This time it's also unlimited, so you can take your time deciding...
ま、セットで買わないとあの、ついてこないんだけど（笑）。
Well, the bonus won't come unless you buy the set (laughs).
ぜひぜひ買っていただけたらなと思います！
I really hope you'll buy it!
そしてこのあとね、メンバーシップ限定のライブもありますので、
And after this, there will be a members-only live,
ぜひメンバーシップに入って待機していただけると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you joined and waited there.
メンバーシップライブも頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best for the membership live too!
待っててねー！
Wait for me!